<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/running-adventures/assets/xslt/atom.xslt" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/running-adventures/assets/css/atom.css" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<id>http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/</id>
	<title>The Running Adventures of the Still Standing Muffin Man</title>
	<updated>2019-07-06T11:34:32+01:00</updated>

	<subtitle>A journey in the world of long distance running</subtitle>

	
		
		<author>
			
				<name>muffin man</name>
			
			
			
		</author>
	

	<link href="http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link href="http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />

	<generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator>

	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/training/training-plan-post/</id>
			<title>I Love It When A Plan Comes Together a.k.a. Training Plan</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/training/training-plan-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Love It When A Plan Comes Together&lt;br/&gt; a.k.a. Training Plan" />
			<updated>2019-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>muffin man</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>After a few months of running for the sake of it, it was time to look at how a runner trains to maximize its potential. </summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/training/training-plan-post/">&lt;p&gt;After running two half-marathon races and having registered for a trail and a full marathon, 
a proper training plan was, somehow, required. Why having a training plan? Simply to run &lt;strong&gt;smart&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of information on the web and in the bookshops… But, after doing some filtering,
I ended up with with 5 YouTube videos to be watched, few YouTube channels to follow for tips and cool stories, and two books.
It is of course a very personal choice and I am sure that I missed a lot of good stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-types-of-training&quot;&gt;4 types of training&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these four short YouTube videos, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jack_Daniels_(coach)&quot;&gt;Jack Daniels PhD&lt;/a&gt;, two-time Olympics medalist in modern pentathlon and named “The World’s Best Coach” by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.runnersworld.com&quot;&gt;Runner’s World magazine&lt;/a&gt;, 
explains the different types of training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know what you think, but no, the man speaking in these videos is not involved in the distillation of whisky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1- Easy Run&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/veAQ73OJdwY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2- Threshold Training&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dxJVtPT6rHo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3- Interval Training&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7dQEwJhHWXk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4- Repetition Training&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BGQKlSU4HQM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-the-pace&quot;&gt;About the pace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may then ask how to find the the paces associated to each type of training. 
The good news is that Jack Daniels takes care of that too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://runsmartproject.com/calculator/&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/daniels-vdot-logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you enter in the table below your last race distance and race time you will obtain 
the recommended paces of each training type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://runsmartproject.com/calculator/embed/index.php?title=false&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;520&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you did race a 1h45 half-marathon, the recommended paces for the each types of training are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/daniels-paces-1h45-half.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-little-note-on-the-paces&quot;&gt;A little note, on the paces.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the suggested paces graph, you could note that there is a &lt;strong&gt;“no man’s land” pace zone&lt;/strong&gt; between the easy run pace 5:09min/km and the threshold pace 4:51min/km.
In other words, we should not run in this zone. The bad news is that I was essentially running in the &lt;strong&gt;“no man’s land” pace zone&lt;/strong&gt; at about 5:30min/km, 
but the good news is that, now, I know I should not!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;no-pain-no-gain&quot;&gt;No pain No gain?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Jack Daniels’s videos are actually enough. But I also found the following one-hour long video very useful too. 
Especially the easy run training, the training plan, and the periodization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pqo5AbcELFM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;few-youtube-channels&quot;&gt;Few YouTube channels&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Run Smart Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/runsmartproject&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;../../images/run_smart_project-logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vo2maxProductions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/Vo2maxProductions&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;../../images/vo2max_productions-logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Running Wild&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/RunningWild2Believe&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;../../images/running_wild-logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Run Experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/TREtherunexperience&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;../../images/run_experience-logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-little-bit-of-reading&quot;&gt;A little bit of reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack Daniels… again! Plus a book dedicated to marathon training was more than enough for me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Daniels-Running-Formula-3rd-Jack/dp/1450431836/ref=sr_1_1?keywords=jack+daniels+running&amp;amp;qid=1558174667&amp;amp;s=gateway&amp;amp;sr=8-1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;../../images/running_formula.jpg&quot; /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Advanced-Marathoning-Peter-Pfitzinger/dp/0736074600/ref=sr_1_4?keywords=marathon+training&amp;amp;qid=1558174711&amp;amp;s=gateway&amp;amp;sr=8-4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/advanced_marathoning.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>

			
				<category term="training" />
			
			

			<published>2019-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/races/nice-half-matrathon-post/</id>
			<title>Nice Half-Marathon a.k.a. !?&amp;∞&amp;¡¿</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/races/nice-half-matrathon-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nice Half-Marathon a.k.a. !?&amp;∞&amp;¡¿" />
			<updated>2019-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>muffin man</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>I tried to avoid this race, but there was not escape.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/races/nice-half-matrathon-post/">&lt;p&gt;After the &lt;a href=&quot;/running-adventures/races/wimbledon-half-marathon-post/&quot;&gt;Wimbledon Common half-marathon&lt;/a&gt; on April the 7th, I wanted to focus on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.utmc.fr&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UTMC half-marathon&lt;/a&gt;… But, again, I had no escape and I raced the Nice half-marathon on May the 5th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-race-goal-time-tuesday&quot;&gt;The race goal time Tuesday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six days before the race I was able to get an estimate of my race goal time. It was actually easy, I did not manage to go under 1h45 (4:55min/km or 8min/mile) at Wimbledon Common, but, in Nice, I will! 
Let me remind you that for the Wimbledon Common race:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was sick…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I started too fast…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I cried…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a matter of fact, all those points can be easily resolved:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not get sick!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not start too strong!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not cry!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy, isin’t it?… But, as nothing goes usually according to plan, I realized that another important item should be added:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not get injured!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;easy-run-wednesday&quot;&gt;Easy Run Wednesday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the race was on Sunday, I decided to only go for a little run on Wednesday (6min/km pace). And it was just fine, it was just fine until I started to fell a little bit of pain in my right thigh…
A little bit pain, and a little bit more, and a little more, and then a lot of pain… 
&lt;br /&gt; I finished the “run” walking, and even the walk was painful… !?&amp;amp;∞&amp;amp;¡¿. 
&lt;br /&gt; So what to do? Well, not much, simply resting and hoping that tomorrow it will become good again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thirsty-thursday&quot;&gt;Thirsty Thursday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day after, it was far from good… It was actually bad. The pain was still there and I had not choice but to extent my race goal time… From 1h45 to 2h… It was that bad… I was walking like a duck…  And ducks are not known for there running capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But life should go on, and since I flushed my race goal time to the toilet, I decided to join the usual Thirsty Thursday party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan was simple, to go to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jerusalembarandkitchen.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jerusalem bar&lt;/a&gt; with some good friends from work, have fun, drink a unique glass of wine, and go home, early. Injured or not, I was still racing on Sunday!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/jerusalem_bar.jpeg&quot; align=&quot;middle&quot; /&gt; 
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, somehow, the unique glass of wine became the unique bottle of wine… But let me reassure you, I was not drinking the bottle alone, &lt;strong&gt;Jordy&lt;/strong&gt; was helping me! Then, the unique bottle of wine became somehow three botttes of wine, coupled with few tequilla shots, and one bad cigarette… And after a lot of cheers (obviously), a lot of dancing, and a lot of fun, I managed to go home at 1am. Pretty early right?… Well, what can I say, I really enjoyed the party…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hungover-friday&quot;&gt;Hungover Friday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day went as you would expect, I was still injured and, on top of that, I had a teeny-tiny hangover… But totally worth it! 
I used this day to finetune the race playlist by removing all the emotional songs that could make me cry! And, trust me on that, I did a pretty good job!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;trip-to-nice-saturday&quot;&gt;Trip to Nice Saturday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally back to the race mood, &lt;strong&gt;Rambo Chérie&lt;/strong&gt; and I arrived in Nice around 5pm. Yes guys, &lt;strong&gt;Rambo Chérie&lt;/strong&gt; was racing the half too! 
We landed to Nice around 5pm, went directly to collect our race numbers, and joined the Dream Team in the Vieux Nice. But, this time, we skipped the &lt;a href=&quot;/running-adventures/story/the-start-post/&quot;&gt;rum baba&lt;/a&gt;…
They were all good! Except &lt;strong&gt;Aurélia&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Bergamot&lt;/strong&gt;, they both got injured and dedided to skip the race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How &lt;strong&gt;Aurélia&lt;/strong&gt; injured her adductor muscle remains a mystery… The most likely hypothesis are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;doing the splits without warm up.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;going for long horse ride.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;doing the splits without warm up while riding a horse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But nobody really knows, or dares to ask. Even if &lt;strong&gt;Aurélia&lt;/strong&gt; is pure kindness, no one wants to push it…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On his side, &lt;strong&gt;Bergamot&lt;/strong&gt; managed to get injured by simply getting out of bed without streching… Yep. &lt;strong&gt;Bergamot&lt;/strong&gt; is kind of stiff…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, a reduced Dream Team, composed of &lt;strong&gt;Barbie Girl&lt;/strong&gt;, Chamomile, &lt;strong&gt;Rambo Chérie&lt;/strong&gt;, and I, will be racing tomorrow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-concert-saturday&quot;&gt;The concert Saturday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The evening before the race day you just want to eat and go to sleep as fast as possible… not even drinking a unique glass of wine! But &lt;strong&gt;Barbie Girl&lt;/strong&gt;’s band was performing tonight in a bar… So we all went… We all enjoyed the concert! And we all drank a unique glass of wine and some smoked a unique cigarette…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not the ideal day before the race type of night… But totally worth it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ranbo Chérie, Camomille and I finally arrived at &lt;strong&gt;Bergamot&lt;/strong&gt;’s place around midnight, and started to swear in a multitude of different languages when we set up the alarm at 5:30am…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;race-sunday&quot;&gt;Race Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-morning-coffee&quot;&gt;The morning coffee&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After smashing my phone on the wall to stop the alarm 5:30 alarm, I went to the kitchen for a well needed coffee. But Chamomile was already in there preparing the coffee. I was about to start the usual morning conversion when I looked through the window, and started to contemplate a violent pourdown… Chamomile and I ended up in front of the window holding a coffee, admiring the huge drops of rain falling down, and, between two sips one of us would say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“That’s bad…”,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“That’s just bad”,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“That’s really bad”,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“That’s so bad”,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“That’s so so bad”,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we could have continued… But &lt;strong&gt;Rambo Chérie&lt;/strong&gt; arrived looked at the window, look at us, look at the window again, and simply said, very accurately:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;!?&amp;amp;∞&amp;amp;¡¿&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shoking, for sure, but &lt;strong&gt;Rambo Chérie&lt;/strong&gt; was so right!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if Chamomile was a little bit shaky after hearing what he heard, we all managed to get race ready and left the flat with &lt;strong&gt;Bergamot&lt;/strong&gt;te still sleeping in there.
Along the way to the start line, the rain stopped! That was finally a good news! 
We arrived at the start line at around 7:30am and, after a quick warm up, I decided to change again my goal race time: even if I was still feeling my tight pretty well, it did not not matter, I will al least try to go under 1h45! Hell yeah! Chamonile also targeted 1h45 and suggested we run together. This was an offer that cannot be refused!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-car&quot;&gt;The car&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 7:55am, all the runners discovered that the start time will be postponed. A very nice guy, or better said !?&amp;amp;∞&amp;amp;¡¿, decided to park his car on the race route… The police had to do all the required security checks and remove the car…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-landscape&quot;&gt;The landscape&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Nice half-marathon is mainly along the promenade des Anglais. And in May, the weather is usually perfect to relax:
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/nice_promenade.jpg&quot; align=&quot;middle&quot; /&gt; 
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
But, first, the reduced Dream Team went to the promenade to race, not to relax. And, second, the sky was not blue but grey and the temperature was not around 25º Celsius below 10º Celsius… !?&amp;amp;∞&amp;amp;¡¿.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-race&quot;&gt;The race&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 8:30, we finally go! Let’s just do it!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I switched on my iPod with my finetuned playlist, composed on only one song: Waterloo from ABBA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Sj_9CiNkkn4&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can I say… It looks like I am very emotional!  I may have, indeed, overdone the finetuning, but I was confident enough that I will not cry!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the crowd, Chamomile and I started the race slow at around 5:30min/km. I was happy about that pace but Chamomile started to accelerate to get to the 1h45 flag. !?&amp;amp;∞&amp;amp;¡¿, but I followed. We spent the first 5km slaloming between runners to reach the holly flag. Now we just have to stick with him up to the finish line! At that time I alreasy knew by eart the lyrics of the ABBA song…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Racing with Chamomile was fun! He was speaking all the time! I was not really listening, but I was with him and I was feeling good. After the first 11k, I did not cry nor stop running! My tight was kind of okay, and we decided to pass the flag to gain few extra minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the last 5km, this is when things started to be really tough. I wanted to stop and through away the iPod with this bloody ABBA song. But Chamonile motivated me to keep going. 
“Come on! We will cross the finish line together! Let’s do it!”
And, with the support of Chamonile, and a lot of swearing from my side, we finally crossed the finish line together:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To celebrate we just huged each other and I finally switched off my iPod.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-logs&quot;&gt;The logs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/nice-half-2019.jpg&quot; align=&quot;middle&quot; /&gt; 
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-medals&quot;&gt;The medals&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After few minutes of rest, it was time to collect the medals. One of the guys in charge of the medal distribution was free and we went for him. We looked like a serious man in his 50s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After kindly asking us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Hey guys! So, how did it go?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We were so proud to annonce him that we did it in 1h44! Seing how proud we were, he told us:&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Ah… Ok… But please guys, next time you could at least push it a little bit…”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chamomile and I were both like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WHAT!!!???&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is when we saw a little smile on his face and we all burst into laughs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barbie Girl&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Rambo Chérie&lt;/strong&gt; crossed the finish line few minutes after that. &lt;strong&gt;Rambo Chérie&lt;/strong&gt; also managed to get a new half-marathon PR and her first race medal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;totally-worth-it&quot;&gt;Totally worth it&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This race was crazy. Everything started so bad or, better said, so !?&amp;amp;∞&amp;amp;¡¿, but, somehow everything turned up really good!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, the UTMC!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>

			
				<category term="races" />
			
			

			<published>2019-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/races/wimbledon-half-marathon-post/</id>
			<title>First Race Ever a.k.a. Ain't No Sunshine</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/races/wimbledon-half-marathon-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Race Ever a.k.a. Ain't No Sunshine" />
			<updated>2019-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>muffin man</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>You expected the Nice half-marathon to be my first race... Let me explain... </summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/races/wimbledon-half-marathon-post/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;from-nice-to-wimbledon&quot;&gt;From Nice to Wimbledon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Since we all signed up for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.utmc.fr&quot;&gt;UTMC half-marathon&lt;/a&gt;, the Dream Team kind of reached an unsaid agreement:
&lt;br /&gt; The Nice half-marathon, in May the 5th, was a little bit too close from the UTMC, in July the 21st, 
 let’s just skip it. 
&lt;br /&gt; But I did not want the crazy UTMC trail to be my first race either… 
So, I found another half-marathon, in April the 7th, in Wimbledon Common. 
&lt;br /&gt; That was just perfect! Perfect in theory… In practice, it was something else…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-dream-team&quot;&gt;The Dream Team&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In theory, all the members of the Dream Team would have joined…
&lt;br /&gt; But in practice, I was the only one…
&lt;br /&gt; And I am pretty sure it would have been much funnier!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-playlist&quot;&gt;The playlist&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have loaded my iPod with hundreds of my favorite songs! 
&lt;br /&gt; And, since I am a rock’n’roll kind of guy, the songs will, in theory, help me to run fast enough!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-physical-condition&quot;&gt;The physical condition&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theory, you are at your pick physical level to race…
&lt;br /&gt; But in practice, I managed to catch a cold few days before the race… 
&lt;br /&gt; But it was not that dramatic, I was just full of medicine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-race-time-goal&quot;&gt;The race time goal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In theory, you manage to race under your race time goal…
&lt;br /&gt; I had initially a pretty conservative race goal time of 1h50. 
&lt;br /&gt; But &lt;strong&gt;Bergamot&lt;/strong&gt; spent days to convince me that 
I should run my first harlf-marathon below 1h45.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bergamot&lt;/strong&gt; was actually stating the obvious:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Since I was running at least a half-marathon every Sunday in less than 1h50, it would be &lt;strong&gt;easy&lt;/strong&gt;. Well… make sense, right?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Since I managed to run a half-marathon in 1h46 three weeks before this race, it would be &lt;strong&gt;easy peasy&lt;/strong&gt;. Well… make sense, right?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Since you race faster than you run, it would be &lt;strong&gt;easy peasy lemon squeezy&lt;/strong&gt;. Well… make sense, right?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-race&quot;&gt;The race&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/wimbledon_common.jpg&quot; align=&quot;middle&quot; /&gt; 
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Okay &lt;strong&gt;Bergamot&lt;/strong&gt;! Let’s do it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started strong, a little bit too exited maybe… Following the crowd, I was able to get a 5km Personal Record (PR) and a 10km PR in the first half of the race.
The main problem I then faced was to continue at that pace for the second half… 
By keeping this pace I would have finished around 1h40, pretty cool no?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;when-a-very-specific-song-kicked-in&quot;&gt;When a very specific song kicked in&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then… My iPod decided to play &lt;em&gt;Ain’t no sunshine&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Bill Withers&lt;/em&gt;. 
Don’t get me wrong, I love this song, it is a great song, a song full of emotions…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tIdIqbv7SPo&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; … maybe full of too many emotions!
&lt;br /&gt; I was thinking about &lt;strong&gt;Mademoiselle-Docteur-Chérie-mon-Amour-ma-Femme-de-ma-Vie-mon-Épouse&lt;/strong&gt; a.k.a. &lt;strong&gt;Rambo Chérie&lt;/strong&gt;, not there with me… And I just started to cry, and stopped to run. 
Looks like I am an emotional kind of guy after all. 
&lt;br /&gt; Yeah, I stopped to run because of this song… And also because I was not able to breath neither… 
Let’s say a little bit of both.
And once you stop to run, you will continue to stop…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;race-log&quot;&gt;Race log&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/wimbledon-half-2019.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;race-results&quot;&gt;Race results&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/wimbledon-half-2019-results.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally crossed the finished line with a race time of 1h48.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I learned few valuable lessons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;do not have &lt;em&gt;Ain’t no sunshine&lt;/em&gt; in your playlist.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;do not start the race too strong:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A 5k PR and a 10k PR in a 21km race does not seem right, and I am pretty sure that it is not!&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I heard that the first 2/3 of the race should be run with your legs and the last third with your heart. Well, it clearly does not work for the last 10k of a harlf-marathon.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I was sick.
&lt;br /&gt; Yes, I cried.
&lt;br /&gt; Yes, I did not get a Personal Record on the half-marathon distance.
&lt;br /&gt; But it was so fun! And I am already thinking about the next race…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-next-race&quot;&gt;The next race&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized few days later that the unsaid agreement evoked earlier was void:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rambo Chérie&lt;/strong&gt; really wanted to race the Nice half-marathon.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barbie Girl&lt;/strong&gt; already registered to the Nice half-marathon.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chamomile&lt;/strong&gt; will join the race even if he is playing hard to get for now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay guys! let’s just do it then!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only &lt;strong&gt;Aurélia&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Bergamot&lt;/strong&gt; will not be able to join, but more on that later…&lt;/p&gt;

</content>

			
				<category term="races" />
			
			

			<published>2019-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/running/increasing-weekly-milage-post/</id>
			<title>Increasing Weekly Millage a.k.a. Run Boy Run</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/running/increasing-weekly-milage-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Increasing Weekly Millage a.k.a. Run Boy Run" />
			<updated>2019-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>muffin man</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>After running/walking my first half-marathon, it was time to be more consistent and run more.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/running/increasing-weekly-milage-post/">&lt;p&gt;It was definitely now time to train a little bit more consistently. 
But, before that, the dream decided to meet, party, and run a little 15km in the mountain, to have a little taste of what the 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.utmc.fr&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UTMC half-marathon&lt;/a&gt; 
will reserve us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-little-run-in-the-mountain&quot;&gt;A little run in the mountain&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan was as follows: first we go to 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clans,_Alpes-Maritimes&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Clans&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in the afternoon, then we have a 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raclette&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;raclette&lt;/a&gt;, 
 a good night of rest, a good coffee, and finally, a teeny-tiny run in the mountain as a little clean-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And everything went according to plan, up until after dinner,
when &lt;strong&gt;Barbie Girl&lt;/strong&gt; came-up with an improbable alcoholic drink…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;une-petite-suze&quot;&gt;Une petite Suze?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there is no more improbable drink than the [
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suze_(drink)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Suze&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can guess from the size of its Wikepedia page… The good part of the Suze, is that it can be used in quite different contexts, 
such as to defrost, to clean the oven, to unblock the sink, and, well, to drink. But, &lt;strong&gt;Barbie Girl&lt;/strong&gt; managed, somehow, 
to convince &lt;strong&gt;Bergamot&lt;/strong&gt; that it was drinkable.
To be honest, I preferred to join &lt;strong&gt;Chamomile&lt;/strong&gt; and just have some tea.
Yeah, it was that bad…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;une-petit-trail&quot;&gt;Une petit trail?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Petit… not quite, 15km and 600m of ascent…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/clans15k-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This actually helped us to realize that we will suffer at the UTMC…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;un-petit-peu-de-millage&quot;&gt;Un petit peu de millage?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a month to recover from that &lt;em&gt;petit trail&lt;/em&gt;, I was finally able to accumulate some millage.
I started to watch a few YouTube channels dedicated to running, and I started to follow a 
simple advise: to improve, you have to run more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/5week-log2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was now able to have a long run almost every week (I qualify a long run as a run of 16km or more), 
and a weekly millage of a little bit more that 30km/week. I then decided to increase a little bit more the weekly 
millage…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;un-petit-peu-plus-de-millage&quot;&gt;Un petit peu plus de millage?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/5week-log3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is exactly what I did. With a weekly millage of around 60km/week. 
I was not focusing on the speed, but I still managed to gain a bit of speed and to 
increase my long run up to 27km. In other words, I was staring to be ready for
the Nice half-marathon!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="running" />
			
			

			<published>2019-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/running/route-towards-the-half-marathon-post/</id>
			<title>Route Towards The Half-Marathon a.k.a. Pain</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/running/route-towards-the-half-marathon-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Route Towards The Half-Marathon a.k.a. Pain" />
			<updated>2019-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>muffin man</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>After running my first 10k, I was unstoppable: 20k, 50k, and 100k, watch out, I coming for you! Well...</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/running/route-towards-the-half-marathon-post/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-message-of-hope&quot;&gt;A message of hope&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I perceived my first 10km as &lt;strong&gt;a message of hope&lt;/strong&gt; towards greater things in general,
 and longer distances in particular. But, somehow, I misread the message, it was more like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BtIZitLJ68Q&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, pain was the main outcome of my next weeks of training, and my theory of being unstoppable was kind of wrong…
&lt;br /&gt;To be more specific, never a theory was that wrong…
&lt;br /&gt;Except maybe the 
&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/String_theory&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;String Theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, 
but it is kind of different, 
the &lt;em&gt;String Theory&lt;/em&gt; is 
&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Not_even_wrong&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;not even wrong&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
… 
But let’s forget of the &lt;em&gt;String Theory&lt;/em&gt; for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-practice&quot;&gt;The practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first 10k ever was on July the 22nd, and it took me about two months to reach painfully 15km.
Fun fact, I finally managed to get to 15km on a trail in 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/age,_Arizona&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Page, Arizona&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;at about 1250m above the sea level. 
And I have to admit that it was a lot of fun! Yes the pace was slow, but the landscape was gorgeous! 
&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/first15k.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, on week after, I got my first half-marathon run in 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palo_Alto,_California&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Palo Alto, California&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but this time, at sea level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/first21k.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may notice that I started way too strong, and I actually finished the run walking… 
But again, the good thing is that there is definitely room for improvement!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;when-bergamot-drops-a-bomb&quot;&gt;When &lt;strong&gt;Bergamot&lt;/strong&gt; drops a bomb&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In October 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Bergamot&lt;/strong&gt; was in need of strong sensations. 
And to fill his need, he decided to run. But not a regular run, 
he went for the &lt;strong&gt;crazy 8&lt;/strong&gt; (the route looks like an eight and the distance is crazy!):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;24km of distance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/crazy8-map.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;860m of ascent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/crazy8-deniv.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reaction what two-fold:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1- The first flow of reactions were very supportive:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Congratulations &lt;strong&gt;Bergamot&lt;/strong&gt;!!!!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is it really impressive!!!!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2- The second flow of reactions were a little bit more rough:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ARE YOU CRAZY!!!!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WHAT’S WRONG WITH YOU!!!!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this moment, he innocently tells the Dream Team: 
&lt;br /&gt; “A little trail of 30km, 40km in the mountain is kind of tempting, don’t you think?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-explosion&quot;&gt;The explosion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This comment was followed by silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bergamot&lt;/strong&gt; napped.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chamomile&lt;/strong&gt; made some tea to forget this madness.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barbie Girl&lt;/strong&gt; drunk &lt;em&gt;few&lt;/em&gt; cosmopolitan cocktails to calm down.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aurélia&lt;/strong&gt; engraved her shopping list in a marble plate. She was born in BC remember?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rambo Chérie&lt;/strong&gt; went clay pigeon shooting to find inner peace.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and the &lt;strong&gt;Muffin Man&lt;/strong&gt; looked for trail races…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the bomb exploded:
&lt;br /&gt; Guys, I found a pretty cool trail! 
&lt;br /&gt; It is &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; a half-marathon with a teeny-tiny of ascent… 1100m, the 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.utmc.fr&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UTMC&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; I already registered! You are also coming right?!
&lt;br /&gt; And, after napping, drinking tea, engraving shopping lists in marble, and clay pigeon shooting, the Dream Team signed up for this!!!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>

			
				<category term="running" />
			
			

			<published>2019-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/story/title_explanation-post/</id>
			<title>Title Explanation a.k.a. Crystal Clear</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/story/title_explanation-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Title Explanation a.k.a. Crystal Clear" />
			<updated>2019-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>muffin man</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>You may have wondered what logical steps led to this site title...</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/story/title_explanation-post/">&lt;p&gt;After writing the &lt;a href=&quot;/running-adventures/story/the-start-post/&quot;&gt;Killer BaBa Night&lt;/a&gt; 
and &lt;a href=&quot;/running-adventures/story/the-start-post/&quot;&gt;Bear Beginning&lt;/a&gt; posts, 
I naturally decided to send it to the Dream Team to get their feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-feedback&quot;&gt;The feedback&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to be honest, I did not collect the feedback of all members of the Dream Team…
 When I called &lt;strong&gt;Barbie Girl&lt;/strong&gt;, we did not speak much, 
 she was warming up for a rugby match in which she was playing number 8…
But this is classic &lt;strong&gt;Barbie Girl&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While &lt;strong&gt;Bergamot&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Chamomile&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Rambo Chérie&lt;/strong&gt; were kind of indifferent 
about the post, &lt;strong&gt;Aurélia&lt;/strong&gt; reacted completely differently. She bloody loved it!
She was not able to stop complimenting the concept of the blog in general and the choice of her alias in particular, 
up to the point where it even became embarrassing… But this is classic &lt;strong&gt;Aurélia&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only teeny-tiny suggestion was to make the website title a teeny-tiny more comprehensive for the reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-title&quot;&gt;The title&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Point taken. I have to agree with &lt;strong&gt;Aurélia&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;The Running Adventures of the Still Standing Muffin Man&lt;/strong&gt; is,
 at first sight, pretty cryptic. Cryptic enough to try to bring a little bit of clarity in this crazy world…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;bringing-confusion&quot;&gt;Bringing confusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s first analyze where the confusion is by splitting the title in four parts: 
the &lt;strong&gt;Running Adventures&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;Still Standing&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;Muffin&lt;/strong&gt;, and the &lt;strong&gt;Man&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;the &lt;strong&gt;Running Adventures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Since it is a blog dedicated to long distance running, starting with &lt;strong&gt;The Running&lt;/strong&gt; makes at least sense. 
But is it really an &lt;strong&gt;adventure&lt;/strong&gt;? And even worse, &lt;strong&gt;adventures&lt;/strong&gt; in plural?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Confusing the reader…&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;the &lt;strong&gt;Still Standing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;If the website is all about running, why then mentioning &lt;strong&gt;still&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;standing&lt;/strong&gt;?
It simply defeats the purpose of running…&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Confusing further the reader…&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;the &lt;strong&gt;Muffin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Does the writer like pastries in general and &lt;strong&gt;muffin&lt;/strong&gt; in particular? 
  Does the website is about gluten free vegan muffin recipes to enhance the long distance running performance?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Confusing even further the reader…&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;the &lt;strong&gt;Man&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the &lt;a href=&quot;/running-adventures/story/the-start-post/&quot;&gt;Killer BaBa Night&lt;/a&gt;
post we are now in the &lt;strong&gt;Post Gender Theory Area&lt;/strong&gt;. It is then not possible to determine 
 the biological gender nor the emotional gender.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Overloading the reader of confusion…&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;bringing-clarity&quot;&gt;Bringing clarity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s now answer those questions!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the &lt;strong&gt;Running Adventures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being an emotional kind of guy, all my runs feel like the very first run of Forrest Gum…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IFeUIJMwG4A&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and each one of my runs really feels like an adventure ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the &lt;strong&gt;Still Standing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a run, &lt;strong&gt;Barely Standing&lt;/strong&gt; would be more appropriate but &lt;strong&gt;Still Standing&lt;/strong&gt; is cool!
And more importantly, &lt;strong&gt;Still Standing&lt;/strong&gt; appears in the lyrics of one of my post-running favourite songs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NgzRea-9TuI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, feeling “looking like a true survivor” after a run is definitely a teeny-tiny exaggerated.
But, “feeling like a little kid” is spot on ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the &lt;strong&gt;Muffin&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Man&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a little dedication to the animated movie Shrek in general, and 
a really short scene in particular:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3taMwAEGBVc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This scene made me laughed so much, 
and so hard, that it got stuck in my head. Since then, I was looking
for an opportunity to place “&lt;strong&gt;the Muffin Man&lt;/strong&gt;” somewhere…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to admit that using “&lt;strong&gt;the Muffin Man&lt;/strong&gt;” in a website dedicated to
running is a bit of a stretch, but it is good enough for me. And I hope it
is good enough for you too ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title should by now be crystal clear… (of course, figuratively speaking).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="story" />
			
			

			<published>2019-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/running/before-the-start-post/</id>
			<title>Before The Start a.k.a. The Bear Beginning</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/running/before-the-start-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Before The Start a.k.a. The Bear Beginning" />
			<updated>2019-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>muffin man</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>As mentioned in the previous post, I have begun to run before the Killer BaBa night. This post describes how it went...</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/running/before-the-start-post/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-doubtful-analogy&quot;&gt;A doubtful analogy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first weeks of running could actually be resumed by a simple analogy: It is like &lt;strong&gt;making love to a bear&lt;/strong&gt;… (figuratively speaking).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figuratively speaking, for sure. But, somehow, the side effects look surprisingly similar:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dizziness&lt;/strong&gt;. It is indeed not so hard to imagine that one of the &lt;strong&gt;making love to a bear&lt;/strong&gt; effects is dizziness… 
  Pretty obvious right?…
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;And actually, if you do not breath enough while running - which, trust me, will happen - you will get really dizzy!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dehydration&lt;/strong&gt;. It is indeed not so hard to imagine that one of the &lt;strong&gt;making love to a bear&lt;/strong&gt; effects is dehydration…
  Pretty obvious right?…
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;And actually, if you do not drink enough before the run, during the run, or after the run - which, trust me, will happen - You will get really dehydrated!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pain Localized in the Lower Part of The Body&lt;/strong&gt;. It is indeed not so hard to imagine that one of the &lt;strong&gt;making love to a bear&lt;/strong&gt; effects is pain localized in the lower body parts…
  Pretty obvious right?…
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;And actually, while starting to run, you will stimulate, in a not so gentle way, muscles, tendons, and ligaments localized in the lower part of your body… 
  And they will let you know that they do not like it at all! Which, trust me, will happen.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scars&lt;/strong&gt;. It is indeed not so hard to imagine that one of the &lt;strong&gt;making love to a bear&lt;/strong&gt; effects is getting scars…
  Pretty obvious right?…
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;And actually, if you do not lift your feet high enough you will trip, fall down, and smash the ground! Which, trust me, will happen.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-conclusion&quot;&gt;A conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may then ask, why not just stopping?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good question! Well, first, the &lt;strong&gt;making love to a bear&lt;/strong&gt; side effects disappear, and,
second, it is really fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;running-log&quot;&gt;Running log&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prefer to warn you, it will not be impressive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/strava_log_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
The number in the green circles represent the distance runned in a day (in km not in miles!). 
Not very impressive right? But it is actually okay, there will be a lot room for improvement!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;first-10k-ever&quot;&gt;First 10k ever&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I finished my first 5 weeks of running by doing a 10k!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/first10k.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was pretty happy about that! I wanted now to share this crazy news with my friends in France. 
And, precisely, I was going to visit them 2 weeks later. 
I was looking forward to it, they were apparently pretty enthusiastic about a restaurant, 
and most specifically its dessert menu…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking about how the  &lt;a href=&quot;/running-adventures/story/the-start-post/&quot;&gt;Killer BaBa Night&lt;/a&gt; 
 turned out… Something went definitively wrong! 
I just wanted to brag a bit about running my first 10k in less than 1h,
 which is, indeed, not that impressive… 
And now I signed up for a half-marathon (21.1km) with guys running it in less that 1h45…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I actually heard the &lt;strong&gt;bear expression&lt;/strong&gt; quite recently in a business related discussion… 
Maybe you wonder now what type of job I am doing… Good question!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For people still using the imperial unit system (just in case): 1mile ~ 1.61km.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This post will now be referred to as the &lt;strong&gt;Bear Beginning&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="running" />
			
			

			<published>2019-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/story/the-start-post/</id>
			<title>The Start a.k.a. The Killer BaBa night</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/story/the-start-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Start a.k.a. The Killer BaBa night" />
			<updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>muffin man</name>
					
					
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>The moment everything really started was not my first run, nor my first 10k without stopping, nor even my first half-marathon without blood in my mouth...</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/running-adventures/story/the-start-post/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-decor&quot;&gt;The decor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/vieux_nice.jpg&quot; align=&quot;middle&quot; /&gt; 
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moment everything really started was in Summer 2018 during a dinner at the terrace of a restaurant in 
Nice - South of France, at the terrace of a restaurant in the &lt;em&gt;Vieux Nice&lt;/em&gt;; 
with a lot of good food, a lot of good wine, one bad cigarette, and with a few good friends, 
or better said, a Dream Team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-dream-team&quot;&gt;The Dream Team&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To respect the privacy and integrity of the people involved in those running adventures, aliases will be used.
Please note that, since we are now in a &lt;strong&gt;Post Gender Theory Era&lt;/strong&gt;, 
the biological gender cannot be deduced from the alias… 
So, without further ado, let me briefly introduce the Dream Team:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;---aurelia-&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aurelia_Cotta&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;../../images/aurelia.jpg&quot; /&gt;  Aurelia &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Born in BC, &lt;strong&gt;Aurélia&lt;/strong&gt; is known and respected in 
the Dream Team for both her infinite kindness and her colossal knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;--barbie-girl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barbie_Girl&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/barbie_girl.jpg&quot; /&gt;  Barbie Girl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
After being part of the Danish-Norwegian dance-pop group Aqua, 
&lt;strong&gt;Barbie Girl&lt;/strong&gt; left the North of Europe to dedicate her life to her two passions: 
fashion and rugby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;-chamomile&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chamomile&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/chamomile.jpg&quot; /&gt; Chamomile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
While &lt;strong&gt;Chamomile&lt;/strong&gt; is not as kind as &lt;strong&gt;Aurélia&lt;/strong&gt;, but, who would really be able to?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Chamomile&lt;/strong&gt; has the gift of bringing calm and happiness in the Dream Team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;--bergamot&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bergamot_orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/bergamot.jpg&quot; /&gt;  Bergamot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Bergamot&lt;/strong&gt; is able to find the perfect balance of sweetness and bitterness to keep, somehow, things interesting.
Interesting enough to be the best man of my wedding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;-miss-doctor-sweetheart-love-the-woman-of-my-life-my-wife&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/cherie.jpg&quot; /&gt; Miss-Doctor-Sweetheart-Love-the-Woman-of-my-Life-my-Wife&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait, this alias is a little bit too explicit and a little bit too long… So let us change it a bit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;--rambo-chérie&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Rambo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;../../images/rambo.jpg&quot; /&gt; Rambo Chérie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much better!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that the introductions are done, let us go back to this dinner and, 
more specifically, the break before the dessert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-innocent-phrase&quot;&gt;An innocent phrase&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were finishing our glasses of wine while waiting for the dessert. 
The dessert will reveal to be a huge 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rum_baba&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rum baba&lt;/a&gt;, 
with more rum than baba, and which will kill us all later 
(figuratively speaking, of course…).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waiting for the soon to be killer Baba, I told the table:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“By the way guys, &lt;strong&gt;Rambo Chérie&lt;/strong&gt; and I started to run a bit…”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barbie Girl&lt;/strong&gt; immediately jumped on me (figuratively speaking of course):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Next May there is the half-marathon of Nice! I will register! Do you want to register? Better if I register you! Wait we cannot register now… But as soon that we can we register! Deal?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rare are the moments where I do not want to speak, this moment was one of those… Having nothing to say, I decided to light a cigarette and wait for the storm to pass… But it did not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-storm&quot;&gt;The storm&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between my first and second drag, I discovered that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bergamot&lt;/strong&gt; already run the half of Nice under 1h45!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chamomile&lt;/strong&gt;  already run the Toulouse half-marathon under 1h35!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barbie Girl&lt;/strong&gt; runs few half-marathons and marathons every year, quote “for fun” unquote.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aurelia&lt;/strong&gt; runs the marathon under 3h, quote “easy” unquote!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-trap&quot;&gt;The trap&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK guys, few comments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;First, we all need to calm down.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Second, we should clearly speak a little bit more because I had no clue you were doing all that shit…&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Third, okay guys… Challenge accepted!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With so much peer pressure, I just had no escape…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, the killer Baba arrived, and the rest is just fun blurry history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is simply how it really started…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are now curious about how it was before the start, please visit the next 
&lt;a href=&quot;/running-adventures/story/the-start-post/&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>

			
				<category term="story" />
			
			

			<published>2019-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		</entry>
	
</feed>